JUJUTSU KAISEN
Maki?
Episode 17: Kyoto Sister School Exchange Event - Group Battle 3 -
She's just a weakling.
She can't even see curses.
She's just a normal person
swinging around cursed tools.
She's forever a fourth-grade.
Why is she even a jujutsu sorcerer at all?
Break's over.
Okay.
I see.
That's a relief.
Stupid Mai!
This woman is incredibly strong!
She's using a longer weapon,
so I'd like to close the distance,
but it's all I can do
to dodge and parry her!
If she were using the blade,
I would've died twice!
She's only fourth-grade?!
She could easily defeat
second-grade cursed spirits!
And how is she able to swing such a long sword
in this forest with so much stuff in the way?!
New Shadow Style: Simple Domain!
This allows me to attack anything that
enters the 2.21-meter radius of my domain
on full-auto reflex.
It's released if my feet move from
the point they're at when it's activated.
On top of that,
my Quick Draw is specialized
against enemies attacking head-on.
It's the fastest technique of the
New Shadow School, wrapping my blade
in cursed energy while it's in
the sheath to accelerate it.
But don't think this will settle the match.
Focus my full strength
on creating an opening first.
Iaijutsu, huh?
Looks like she has some trick, too.
But there's a difference in our reach.
Rather than hit me, she likely wants to knock
away my cursed tool and create an opening.
In which case...
She broke it?!
She's throwing away her
reach advantage now?!
She threw it?!
A hidden weapon?!
Her intuition's sharp!
She's trying to close the gap with a decoy!
My legs moved!
But that's fine. I'll pull back and
draw her in just close enough, then—
Aikidou?! What a clever woman!
Huh?
Nice sword you've got here.
Sword-stealing?
Give it back?
What an interesting girl.
You should promote her
to second-grade already.
I feel the same way,
but the Zenin clan keeps getting in the way.
They should just change their
position and accept her already.
I just can't understand such
restraints, aside from money.
I see you're just as miserly as ever.
More importantly, the footage showing
the area around Yuuji keeps cutting out a lot.
Animals are fickle.
Sharing my senses with them is tiring, too.
Huh? Is that true?
Let's be blunt. Which side
are you on, Mei-san?
Which side?
I'm on money's side.
There's no value to anything
that can't be traded for money.
You can't make money out of it, after all.
Just how much have you saved up?
I don't know what he's planning,
but it won't be that easy to
deal with Yuuji anymore.
Oh, they're moving.
All the cursed spirits released
into the area have charms on them,
and when the cursed spirit disappears,
Curse
the corresponding charm here, in the viewing
area, is extinguished simultaneously.
Each charm is extinguished
differently according to
the cursed energy registered beforehand.
Tokyo
When the Tokyo school
exorcises one, they burn red.
Kyoto
When the Kyoto school
exorcises one, they burn blue.
Since Maki-san is in the match, any extinguished
by unregistered responses burn red, as well.
Tokyo
One to one, huh?
No one's paying enough attention to the game.
Why can't they just get along?
They must take after you, Utahime.
You're the only one I have an issue with!
By the way, Panda-kun's
the one who exorcised it.
Lucky!
Get down here, you damn witch!
I've come down a few times already.
Hurry up and try to catch me, first-year!
Her cursed energy wind
is strong enough to lift me!
It hurts like hell when pebbles
and branches get caught in it, too!
If I drop my guard, it'll gouge my flesh!
How dare you hurt my precious face?
A scar on the face is a
badge of honor for a man.
Though it's only a flaw on a woman.
Huh?
You think being a jujutsu sorcerer
is all about strength, don't you?
And it actually is.
That's only for men.
Huh?
Even if they are strong, women have to
be cute, or they'll be undervalued.
Of course, even if they're cute, they'll still
be undervalued if they're not also strong.
Do you get it?
They don't demand strength
from female jujutsu sorcerers.
They demand perfection!
And on top of that,
Mai-chan is also fighting against
even more outrageous demands.
I get that you're a pain in the ass!
She's only a first-year, and she's
already used to fighting?
She's still going strong,
no matter how often I blast her.
I'm used to getting knocked around.
If I up my output any further,
I might kill her.
No, that's just an excuse.
The main reason I can't attack her
is Inumaki-kun.
Cursed speech uses the power of words.
It imbues cursed energy into sound,
so you just have to protect your brain
and your ears with cursed energy.
Cursed speech is a technique specialized
for use against cursed spirits.
Like I said before, it's nothing for a sorcerer
to be afraid of if you know it's coming.
Conversely, if you don't know whether or not
it's coming, you're constantly distracted.
I'm not used to protecting the inside
of my head in the first place...
He's such a nuisance whether he's here or not!
All done with your lecture?!
Perfection is easy compared
to what's demanded of Mai-chan!
She's from the Zenin clan, one of the three major clans of elite jujutsu sorcerers.
Perfection is expected
as a matter of course there.
"Inherit the Zenin clan's
hereditary technique."
Any who don't meet that demand start their sorcerer lives as failures.
Among those, women aren't even
allowed to stand at the starting line.
Without the Zenin clan lineage,
they're not considered jujutsu sorcerers.
And if they're not jujutsu sorcerers,
they're not considered people.
She's lived her entire life with such scorn
in a family without a shred of affection.
Can you imagine how much
Mai-chan and others suffered
just to obtain what we
enjoy as a matter of course?
Why don't you try thinking that
over with that brain of yours
that confuses curses for friends?
Shut up.
You think misfortune is
a free pass to do anything?
What, then?
You're satisfied with those who are blessed
getting trash-talked behind their backs?
That's how Saori-chan...
I can't stand her,
regardless of her upbringing,
and I love Maki-san, who
endured the same upbringing.
Have you all even bothered to
think about what kind of person
the idiot you're trying to curse is?
What makes us obligated to meet such
perfection or such absurd demands?
Is your entire life just a job?!
Straw Doll Technique: Hairpin!
This is why she kept shooting those
nails that didn't land any hits?!
Tsk!
You might have brought me down,
but you still won't reach me!
No, I reached you.
This is plenty!
My broom's bristle?
She grazed it just now?
I don't give a damn about
"men" this and "women" that!
You can keep that shit to yourselves!
I love myself when I'm pretty
and all dressed up!
And I love myself when I'm being strong!
I am...
Kugisaki Nobara!
I can't control my broom!
If I hit her with my hammer,
I might kill her.
So...
A squeaky hammer?!
One more time!
Just barely within effective range.
I'm so glad it hit.
JUJUTSU KAISEN
Hello? Momo?
Don't worry, it was a rubber bullet.
More importantly, that light
was Ultimate Cannon, right?
But I can't get in touch with Mechamaru.
If he was cornered enough to use such
a powerful technique, and now this,
he most likely lost.
Panda will likely be returning.
You should leave that spot and
support everyone from the air.
We're all in trouble without you.
Yeah.
Mai-chan, I...
It's all right, Momo. I know.
Yeah.
What, not going to call your friends?
I don't mind going two-on-one.
There are many ways to enjoy this, right?
I could have everyone beat you together,
but I'd like to enjoy you...
by myself.
Call me "Onee-chan," little sister.
What do you think of Maki-san?
She'll be mad no matter how I answer!
I-I think she's a wonderful woman.
Huh? I'm talking about as a sorcerer.
Oh, that? Good...
Honestly, I still don't know
that much about jujutsu,
but she's really strong in a fight.
Maybe it's her balance? The way
she walks is scary on its own.
Maki-san's a fourth-grade.
Huh? Seriously?
Her family's an annoying clan of sorcerers,
so after she kind of
emancipated herself and left,
they've been interfering with her promotion.
I thought families of jujutsu sorcerers
welcomed powerful sorcerers.
They won't acknowledge what
they've already rejected,
because they're idiots.
But if she performs well
at the exchange event
and her name gets spread around,
it'll be harder for them to harass her like that.
So let's start by winning the group battle!
Fight like you're going to die again!
Sure.
I can hear you.
Jeez.
I shouldn't let myself get distracted.
What are you smiling about?!
So what if she hides out of sight?
Is she an idiot, trying
to gain distance from me?
Tsk!
From below?!
I already knew.
Maki has a talent I don't.
Have you heard about Ougi's daughters?
One can't even see curses,
let alone use techniques.
Twins are a sign of ill fortune.
This might actually be a good thing.
I couldn't bear to see
an eldest son as a servant.
Mai.
What's the matter? Hurry up.
No.
What is it?
We'll get in trouble if we're late again.
They're there.
Again?
All right, fine.
Are you ho... ho...
Come on.
Close your eyes.
Huh?
If you can't see them,
it's the same as if they're not there.
You've always acted like you had no fear
and plowed forward toward your future.
I hated you.
You're leaving the clan, Maki?
You have plenty of servants, right?
Don't worry, though. I'll come
back someday, Clan Leader.
Why would you return?
Because I'm going to be
the head of the Zenin clan!
Then I'll put you through
ordeals befitting that!
Do as you please.
And Mai, as well.
She has nothing to do with this.
Liar.
I hate you!
You fired six shots!
I won't let you reload!
I hate you!
Which is why
I never told you about my first love
or my technique!
"Construction" uses one's cursed energy
to create matter from nothing.
It differs from the manifestation
of an innate domain within the
barrier of a domain expansion.
The matter produced by Construction doesn't
disappear when the cursed technique ends.
Because of that, it consumes
a lot of cursed energy
and puts a heavy strain on the body.
Creating one bullet a day is Mai's maximum.
That's why she uses a revolver to create
an obvious bluff of her bullet count.
I win.
She caught the bullet?
Ow...
I shouldn't touch that with my bare hands.
Maki has a talent I don't.
She's similar to Mechamaru,
with a Heavenly Pact that's
somewhat the opposite.
Normally, she would have been
born with a cursed technique.
But in exchange for that,
she was granted superhuman
physical abilities.
The Zenin clan wouldn't acknowledge it.
That talent I lacked.
I think we can call this settled?
Why did you leave the clan?
Huh? Do I have to spell it out?
You joined Jujutsu Tech
yourself, didn't you?
I...
never wanted to be a jujutsu sorcerer!
It's your fault!
Because you tried so hard to be one,
I was forced to put forth effort, too!
I'm so sick of trying so hard,
facing pain and scary things!
What was so bad about being
ordered around back home?!
We could have just done a few
chores and lived a normal life!
Why wouldn't you stay at
the bottom with me?
Because I would have
hated myself if I did that.
That's the only reason.
Sorry.
Onee-chan, don't let go!
I won't let go.
Never?
Jeez, give it a rest.
Never leave me behind.
Of course I won't.
We're sisters.
You liar.
I hate you.
Kyoto Sister School Exchange Event Group Battle
Zenin Mai
Kugisaki Nobara
— Retired
Juju Stroll
I'm hungry.
If I recall, the edamame I had left over
from lunch was in the fridge...
Sorry.
Please look at least a little guilty!
Seafood
Here, have this and forgive me.
No, I'm not interested
in late-night cup ramen.
Hot
Chili
Pepper
Milk
How about this?!
Nishimiya-style
Seafood Cup Ramen
Arrangement!!
Nishimiya-style Seafood Cup Ramen arrangement!
One: use scissors to chop up hot chili peppers
into the seafood cup ramen!
Two: fill the container halfway with milk.
Three: add hot water up to the line inside!
Since we're using milk,
make sure the water's boiling hot!
I-It's good!
This is really good!
Right?
Maybe I'll try it next time, too.
You could've just eaten
this if it's so good.
Well, you still pay for late-night
cup ramen the next day.
Uh-huh.
Episode 18:
Sage